Guide to the Frank Fish Walker Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Frank Fish Walker papers
1934-1946
SC0189
Walker, Frank Fish, 1896-1978
7 Linear feet
Correspondence, reports, speeches, a scrapbook, and other papers largely relating to Mr. Walker's years in finance with some materials pertaining to his positions at Stanford.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Frank Fish Walker, 1978.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Financial vice-president at Stanford University (1940-1945); trustee (1939-1940). Prior to his affiliation with Stanford, he was a successful financier and stockbroker in New York, working with Blyth, Witter and Company and Eastman, Dillon and Company.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, reports, speeches, a scrapbook, and other papers largely relating to Mr. Walker's years in finance with some materials pertaining to his positions at Stanford.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Board of Trustees.; Stanford University. Financial vice-president.; Walker, Frank Fish, 1896-1978; Capitalists and financiers.; Minutes.; Speeches.
Collection Contents
- General Correspondence, incoming/outgoing, 1937-1946; Series 1
  General Correspondence - incoming/outgoing. The letters are arranged alphabetically by correspondent's last name. Where more than one letter to or from an individual is included, the letters are further arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence: Adams through Awl, 1941-1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Adams, Addinsell, Aetna, Agnew, Albert, Allen, Alvord, Ambrose, Anderson, Armstrong, Aten, Avery, Awl
  - Correspondence: Bacon and Co. through Buyritan, 1941-1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Bacon, Bailey, Baldwin, Banker, Barclay, Barker, Barton, Bashore, Bates, Beal, Becker, Beckett, Beeger, Bernjard, Bing, Blackman, Bliss, Blodget, Bogert, Bowman, Boyle, Bradford, Breeden, Brent, Brigham, British War Relief, Broderick, Brooke, Brookings Institute, Brown, Browne, Bruns, Bryant, Bucklin, Bull, Bullock, Bunker, Burdett, Burlingame, Bush, Buyritan
  - Correspondence: California Historical Society through Cuthbertson, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    California Historical Society, Carlson, Carter, Cavalier, Chace, Chamberlain, Chandler, Chapin, Chickering, Clark, Birge Clark, Cohu, Cole, Coleman, Commercial and Financial Chronicle, Connely, Coonan, Cornish, Cottrell, Coulson, Craig, Crandall, Crary, J.C. Cross, R.W. Cross, E. Cutler, G. Cultler, L.W. Cutler, Sr., L.W. Cutler, Jr., Cuthbertson
  - Correspondence: Dana Co. through Dyson, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Dana Co., Davidson, Davis, Dean, Deane, Dee, Desherow, Dillman, J. Ditz, G. Ditz, Dixon, Dodds, Dodsan, Dolan, Douglass, Dow, Downey, F.S. Downing, P.M. Downing, Dun, Duniway, Dutton, Dyson
  - Correspondence: Eaton through Eurich, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Eaton, Ebbott, Eberstadt, Editor and Publisher (magazine), Edwards, Ehrman, Ellinger, C.K. Elliott, H.C. Elliott, Ellis, Elwood, Ely, Emerson, Erb, Eurich
  - Correspondence: Facciolla through Fuller, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Facciolla, Faye, Fisher, Fitting, A.S. Flack, C. Flack, Flood, Forbes, Forrestal, Fowler, Frasier, Freeman, French, Fried, Friend, C.P. Fuller, K. Fuller
  - Correspondence: Gabriel through Gunther, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Gabriel, Gamble, Garfias, Garfield, General Rayon Co., Georgeson and Co., Gerry, Giannini, Gillespie, Gilmour, Glenn, Goodman, Gordon, Graham, Grainger, Grannis, Graves, Greene, Griffin, Gunther
  - Correspondence: Hahn through Hunter, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Hahn, Hale, Halle, Halsted, Hammet, Hammond, Hanau?, Hanley, Hannah, Hanssen, Harden, Harding, Harris, Hart, Hartman, Haugh, C. Hauser, H.P. Hauser, Hawkins, Hazelwood, Heffner, Heintz, Herndon, Hettinger, Heuer, Hicks, Hieb, Higley, Hill, Hinman, Hirsch, Hobbs, Hodgdonk, Hoffman, Hogate, Holmes, Hoover, Hotaling, Howard, A. Howe, B. Howe, Howell, J. Hunter, T. Hunter
  - Correspondence: Illinois Company through Irwin, 1941-1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Illinois Company, Investment Letters, Inc., "Investment Timing…", Investographs, Irwin
  - Correspondence: Jackson through Joseph, 1941-1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    J.H. Jackson, G. Jackson, Jacobi, Jacobsen, James, F. Jameson, M. Jameson, Jedenoff, Jeidel, Jenkins, Jertberg, Jessup, Jewett, H. Johnson, S.L. Johnson, A.G. Jones, C.T. Jones, E.E. Jones, K.S. Jordan, Josephs
  - Correspondence: Kaiser through Lolb, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Kaiser, Kalb, Kaufman, Keary, Keast, A.S. Keesling, F.V. Keesling, Kefauver, Kelly, Kendrick, P.B. Kennedy, R. Kennedy, Kern, Keyston, Kilpatrick, Kimball, F.B. King, J.H. King, L.S. King, Kinney, Kneass, Knorp, Kolb
  - Correspondence: Lachmund through Lutz, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Lachmund, Laing, Lamb, Langnecker, Lathrop, LeClair, Levison, Levit, E.C. Lipman, F.L. Lipman, Lilly, Limbert, Lloyd, Lochend, Lockwood, Loeb, G. Long, Wm. Long, Loucks, Lutz
  - Correspondence: McBean through McMurphy, 1941-1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    McBean, McCanie, McClanahan, McClelland, McClenahan, McCord, A. McDonald, E.B.M. McDonald, McDonnell, McDuffie, McElroy, McGoey, McGrath, McIntosh, McKellar, McKenna, McKinnon, McLain, McLaine, B.M. McLaughlin, R.P. McLaughlin, D.W. McLellan, R.T. McLellan, McMullin, McMurphy
  - Correspondence: Magill through Musick, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Magill, Mallatratt, Maloney, Mansfield, Manspeaker, Marks, Marsh, Martindell, Marx, J.C. Maxwell, G.L. Maxwell, Maynard, Mein, Mellor, Merrill, Middleton, G.W. Miller, R.V. Miller, Minsch, Mitchell, Mitchum, Montgomery, Moody's, Moran, Morey, R. Morris, W. Morris, Moseley, Musick
  - Correspondence: Nadler through Norris, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Nadler, National Cash Register Co., Neil, Newton, Nordwell, Nourse, Norris
  - Correspondence: Padgett through Pugh, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Padgett, Page, Palmer, Palo Alto Hospital, Parton, Pearce, Penney, Persons, Peter, Petree, Phelps, Ponting, E.J. Power, J.F. Power, A.C. Prendergast, C.W. Prendergast, R.A. Prendergast, Price, Prior, Pugh
  - Correspondence: Rabinowitz through Rutherford, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Rabinowitz, Rand, Randan, L. Raymond, M. Raymond, R. Raymond, Real Estate, Rebele, Rechholtz, "Red", Reed, Rehm, Reid, Republican, H. Reynolds, J. Reynolds, L. Reynolds, R. Reynolds, Rhea, Rible, Rice, Rickard, Riechers, Riley, Ritter, Robertson, Robinson, Rogers, Roseberry, Ross, Rounds, Ruhl, Russell, Rutherford
  - Correspondence: Safro through Spencer, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Safro, Saunders, Schick, Schissler, Schlemner, Scholl, Schroder, Schroeder, Schudt, Schwabacher, Schwartz, Schwarzenbek, Schott, Scribner, Selfridge, Shainwald, Shaughnessy, Shoup, Shriver, Silloway, Simpson, Sisson, Sloss, A.F. Smith, F. Smith, Soares, Spence, Spencer
  - Correspondence: Stamm through Swimm, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Stamm, Stanton, Starke, Starring, Stepp, Stern, J.S. Stevens, L. Stevens, S. Stevens, Stewart, Stillman, Stone, Storey, Stuart, Sullivan, Supple, Swain, Sweet, Swigart, Swimm
  - Correspondence: Taylor through Turner, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Taylor, F.E. Terman, L.M. Terman, E.L. Thompson, W.H. Thompson, Thornton, Tomlinson, Torrey, Townsend, Tripp, Troy, Tully, Turner
  - Correspondence: Uhrig through Volkmann, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Uhrig, Underhill, Union Pacific Railroad, United Airlines, Valentine, Vanderpool, Van Fleet, Van Patten, Vaughn, Veale, Vivian, Volkmann
  - Correspondence: Walker through Worswick, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    B. Walker, D. Walker, I. Walker, N. Walker, Warren, Waterman, Wearin, Webb, Weber, 45 Webster, Weeden, Weinmann, Weinberg, Wentworth, F.C. Wheeler, O.P. Wheeler, Whisler, A.P. White, L. White, R.L. White, Wiggins, Wilbur, Willis, Winkler, D. Witter, G. Witter, J. Witter, Wolford, Wood, Woods, Worswick
  - Correspondence: Yates through Zink, 1941-1945 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Yates, Yost, YMCA, YWCA, Yucca Loma, Zellerbach, Zink
  - Correspondence: Personal matters, 1943 June-December (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Receipts, invitations, travel
  - Correspondence: Personal matters, 1944 January-July (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Invitations, travel arrangements, personal receipts
  - Correspondence: Christmas lists, letters, and cards, 1938-1943 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Christmas letters, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Finance reports, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Investment securities, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: New York trip, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: New York trip, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, Reports: Railroad Commission, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: Real Estate, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Subject Correspondence, incoming/outgoing, 1934-1945; Series 2
  Correspondence - incoming/outgoing under subject headings in chronological order.
  - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Re: Walker's decision to work at Stanford
  - Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Re: Congratulations on Walker's Stanford appointment
  - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Re: Congratulations on Walker's appointment
  - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Stanford Portfolio matters", Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Correspondence
  - Stanford Investment Committee, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Minutes
  - Stanford Investment Committee, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Minutes/agenda
  - Stanford Investment Committee, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Investment Committee, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Insurance, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Selby Lane" - Walker's Atherton property, 1934-1938 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Contributions, taxes, income tax
  - "Selby Lane" - Atherton property, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, information, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Re: Vacation plans, Kingswood School
  - "Personal correspondence", 1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Business transactions
  - Correspondence, 1941 June 20 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Re: Walker dinner, Palace Hotel
  - "Personal correspondence", 1942 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Osborne luncheon, 1942 May 20 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Personal correspondence", 1943 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Re: death of Nellie Walker, F.F. Walker's mother
  - Red Cross, 1941-1943 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Red Cross, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Red Cross, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Protestant Orphanage Society, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Re: Capt. Gene Coldiron
  - Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Re: Frederick Coykendall
  - Correspondence, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Re: Charles S. Hobbs
- General files, 1936-1946; Series 3
  General files organized by subject heading. Includes "Bond Club Material", receipts, etc.
  - Speeches to Medical Alumni, School of Education, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Speeches about Stanford, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Further speeches to Stanford groups, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence on finance and investments with newsclippings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Untitled speech to Alumni Association, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous newsclippings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Stanford's financial situation/campus problems
  - Stanford Associates, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Publications
  - Eastman, Dillon and Co., Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Reports
  - Carnegie Corporation Report on current problems of professional colleges, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Business transactions/mailing list
  - Unpublished manuscript, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    "Insurance for colleges and universities"
  - "Stanford Club matter", Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Memoranda, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Re: Retirement plan for non-academic employees of Stanford University
  - Newsclippings, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Re: Stanford's military plans
  - "Short Rocks", 1936 May (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Vacation
  - Commodities reports, 1940 June-July (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Investment information, Correspondence, re: Investments of universities
  - Bank Statements, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 17)